[Homepage] [LinkedIn] [Google Scholar] Mobile: +852-55192522

ABOUT ME

I obtained my Ph.D. at the Chinese University of Hong Kong and developed interdisciplinary skillsets in both machine learning and system engineering. My current research focuses on using cutting-edge machine learning to model monitoring metrics and improve the reliability and performance of cloud computing systems. Till November 2022, I have published papers in top conferences, including ASE, DSN, ICDCS, WWW, ISSRE, etc. Besides, I also spent time at Microsoft Research Asia, Huawei Cloud, and Ant Financial as a research intern/data analyst intern. Graduating in November 2022, I am open to full-time Quantitative Researcher/ Applied Scientist positions in Hong Kong now. I hold a valid IANG visa and can legally work in Hong Kong.

EDUCATION

The Chinese University of Hong Kong Hong Kong, China Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering; Supervisor: Prof. Michael R. Lyu Aug 2018 - Nov 2022 Sun Yat-Sen University Guangzhou, China B.Eng. in Computer Science and Technology; GPA: 3.9/4.0; National Scholarship (Top 2%) Aug 2014 – June 2018

EXPERIENCE

Huawei Cloud Shenzhen, China Intern June 2020 - May 2022

o Dependency Evaluation in Microservices: Proposed a novel concept to model the state propagation between microservices (i.e., intensity of dependency), and an efficient heuristic algorithm to evaluate the intensity of dependency. Published a conference paper in ASE'2021.

- o Evaluating the Quality of Alerts: Proposed a learning-based framework to evaluate the Quality of Alerts (QoA) to achieve automatic alert governance in the cloud so as to accelerate the alert diagnosis of On-Call Engineers. Published a conference paper in DSN'2022.
- o Multi-modal Learning for System Anomaly Detection: Proposed a multi-modal deep learning model to detect system anomalies on multi-dimensional time series. The conference paper is under review.
- Self-adaptive Resilience Testing: Proposed a self-adaptive approach to automatically evaluate the resilience of microservice systems based on fault injection and multi-dimensional metric analysis. The conference paper is under

Data, Knowledge, Intelligence Group, Microsoft Research Asia (MSRA) Intern

Beijing, China June 2019 - Aug 2019

Email: tim.tyyang@outlook.com

 Root Cause Diagnosis in Azure: Identifying root causes of many incident storms of Azure's cloud services via a heuristic search algorithm in multi-variate incident tickets.

Shenzhen Research Institute, The Chinese University of Hong Kong

Shenzhen, China

Research Assistant

March 2018 - June 2018

 Aspect Sentiment Analysis for App Review: Proposed a novel framework for analyzing user sentiment of app features captured from user reviews. Introduced a new methodology for measuring the sentiment of opinion words (i.e., emotion words), and establishing their relations with corresponding app features. Published a conference paper in WWW'2021.

Institute of Software Engineering and Application, Sun Yat-Sen University

Guangzhou, China April 2016 - Feb 2018

o Panther#: Proposed an algorithm for node embedding in a homogenous network with a novel procedure of biased random walk, which efficiently explores neighborhood similarity and structural similarity even when two nodes are completely disconnected.

Alipay, Alibaba Group

Hangzhou, China

Algorithm Engineer Intern

Iul 2017 - Oct 2017

- o Car Owner Prediction: Core service for all systems in Ant Financial. Created a decision tree model that predicts with high accuracy whether a user has a car based on the user's behavior over a certain period of time. The model passed the internal review and was deployed in the production environment.
- o Anti Cash-out Model: Core risk management service for consumer finance. Utilized distance metric learning to automatically discover the most informative meta-path on heterogeneous information network and prevent cash-out.

South China Research Center of Statistical Science

Guangzhou, China

Intern

Jan 2016 - June 2016

o Diabetic Retinopathy Diagnostic System: Implemented a retinal blood vessel segmentation algorithm based on line tracking. Also developed an auxiliary diagnostic system based on Caffe for diabetic retinopathy detection.

PUBLICATIONS

- ISSRE'22 Tianyi Yang, Baitong Li, Jiacheng Shen, Yuxin Su, Yongqiang Yang, and Michael R. Lyu. 2022. Managing Service Dependency for Cloud Reliability: The Industrial Practice. In Proceedings of the 33rd IEEE International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering.
- DSN'22 Tianyi Yang, Jiacheng Shen, Yuxin Su, Xiaoxue Ren, Xiao Ling, Yongqiang Yang, and Michael R. Lyu. 2021. Characterizing and Mitigating Anti-patterns of Alerts in Industrial Cloud Systems. In Proceedings of the 52nd Annual IEEE/IFIP International Conference on Dependable Systems and Networks.
- Tianyi Yang, Jiacheng Shen, Yuxin Su, Xiao Ling, Yongqiang Yang, and Michael R. Lyu. 2021. AID: ASE'21 Efficient Prediction of Aggregated Intensity of Dependency in Large-scale Cloud Systems. In Proceedings of the 36th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering.
- WWW'21 Tianyi Yang, Cuiyun Gao, Jingya Zang, David Lo, and Michael R. Lyu. 2021. TOUR: Dynamic Topic and Sentiment Analysis of User Reviews for Assisting App Release. In Companion Proceedings of the Web Conference 2021.
- ICDCS'21 Jiacheng Shen, Tianyi Yang, Yuxin Su, Yangfan Zhou, and Michael R. Lyu. 2021. Defuse: A Dependency-Guided Function Scheduler to Mitigate Cold Starts on FaaS Platforms. In Proceedings of the 41st IEEE International Conference on Distributed Computing Systems.
- **CSUR** Shilin He, Pinjia He, Zhuangbin Chen, Tianyi Yang, Yuxin Su, and Michael R. Lyu. 2021. A Survey on Automated Log Analysis for Reliability Engineering. ACM Computing Survey, April 2021.

ONGOING PUBLICATIONS

- (Under review) AVERT: A Self-adaptive Resilience Testing Framework for Microservice Systems
- (Under review) Eadro: Integrating Anomaly Detection and Root Cause Localization on Multi-source Monitoring Data for Microservices
- (Under review) HADES: Heterogeneous Anomaly Detection for Software Systems via Attentive Multi-modal Learning
- (Under review) ScaleStore: Scalable and Fault-Tolerant Key-Value Store on Disaggregated Memory

Honors

Awards

o Postgraduate Studentship, The Chinese University of Hong Kong 2018-2022 2022

o Invited Speaker, The 20th National Software and Application Conference

Competitions

o Meritorious Winner, Mathematical Contest in Modeling 2017

o First Prize, Undergraduate Contest in Mathematical Modeling

PROJECTS

- File System for Block Storage Devices: Implemented a user-space file system that support common file-related system call for block device using FUSE. (https://github.com/yttty/isfs)
- · Assembler & CPU Simulator: Implemented an assembler to compile assembly code and a CPU simulator to execute the machine code. (https://github.com/yttty/exp-isa)

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

• Languages: Python, C++, SQL

Frameworks: Kubernetes, Docker, PyTorch, Spark, FUSE

2016